Okay, great. We have some basic unit tests here.
很好，我们这已经有了一些基础的 Unit 测试了
And we're going to write some staging tests pretty soon.
很快我们就会编写一些 Staging 测试
But before we actually do that, let's go ahead and add the gas estimator.
但在此之前，让我们来先添加一下 "gas estimator"
And we'll see how much gas these contracts in these functions are taking.
我们要看一下这些合约和函数用掉了多少 gas
It looks like the Hardhead gas reporter is already here.
看起来 "hardhat-gas-reporter" 已经准备好了
So let's scroll down. We'll do gas reporter true.
所以让我们往下拉，把 "gasReporter" 修改为 `true`
And we won't do coin market cap here. And we'll just look purely at the GUI.
这里我们就不使用 "coinmarketcap" 了，只看用了多少 gwei
So you can just comment it out like that.
你可以像这样直接注释掉它
Now rerun all of our tests. So we'll say yarn, our test.
现在重新运行我们所有的测试 `yarn hardhat test`
And in doing so we're gonna get that that gas output in that gas report dash text here.
这样我们就会在 "gas-report.txt" 中得到相应的 gas 输出
So looks like all of our tests are passing, which is perfect.
看起来我们所有的测试都通过了，非常完美
Now we can look into our gas report and see what's going on here.
现在我们可以查看一下 "gas-report"，看看都发生了些什么。
i Well, it looks like the fundraising function is taking a decent chunk of gas,
好吧，看起来 "fund" 函数消耗了相当多的 gas
the withdrawal function, take it some guests to
"withdraw" 函数同样消耗了不少 gas
we'd see the min, the max and the average.
我们可以看到最小值("Min")，最大值("Max")以及平均值("Avg")
Of course, we can see how much each one of these contracts cost to actually output.
当然还可以看到每个合约消耗量的输出
We don't really care about the MOQ aggregator of course,
我们倒是不关心 "MockV3Aggregator"
because we're never actually going to use that.
因为我们永远都不会真的用上它
Let's say we look at the average gas for these and we go hmm,
我们来看看它们平均消耗了多少 gas
this looks like it's actually a lot more than what we originally expected.
看起来大大超出了我们最初的预期
Is there a way for us to make this a little bit cheap.
有没有办法能便宜一点呢
If we go back to our funding contract, we look at our withdrawal function.
回到我们的 "FundMe" 合约，看一下我们的 "withdraw" 函数
And we noticed something,
我们注意到了某些东西
oh, there is actually a way to make this a lot cheaper.
哦，确实有个方法可以让它便宜不少
And it has to do with something called storage variables, or these global variables that we've been working with this whole time.
这与我们一直使用的 storage 变量或者说全局变量有关
Let me let me paint you a little picture here,
让我来给你们描述一下
we're gonna look at one of the first gas optimization techniques you can take to drop these down.
我们要通过一种早期的 gas 优化技巧来把成本降下来
And it has to do with an R Funmi. Contract
它要在我们的 "FundMe" 合约中进行操作
these state variables and how they're actually stored
这些状态变量以及它们实际如何存储
and how this contract actually keeps track of all this stuff,
还有这些合约如何跟踪它们，我们要把这些东西都搞清楚
this section is going to be a little bit more advanced.
这个部分略微会有点进阶
So we'll have a note here saying that this is an advanced section,
所以我们这里先说明一下，这是一个进阶部分
if you want to skip over it, you can,
如果你想跳过的话，完全可以
because now we're getting into gas optimizations here,
因为现在我们要做的是 gas 优化相关的事
this information still is really good to know.
但这些知识点仍然是很有用的
So if you want to skip it for now, and then come back later, you absolutely can.
所以如果你打算现在先跳过，之后再返回来看，也完全是可以的
But let's talk about what happens
让我们来讨论一下
when we actually save or store these global variables. Okay, these storage variables.
当我们保存或存储这些全局变量或者说 storage 变量时，到底发生了些什么
Now, everything I'm about to go through is in the documentation.
现在，我要提到的所有内容都来自于这个文档
And there is a link to this, of course, in the GitHub repo associated with this course,
链接放在了课程关联的 GitHub 仓库中
whenever we have one of these global variables, or these variables that stay permanently,
当我们有这么一些全局变量或者说永久保留的变量时
they're stuck in something called storage,
它们都被存放在了一个被称为 "Storage" 的区域里
you can think of storage as a big giant array, or a giant list of all the variables that we actually create.
你可以将 "Storage" 想象为一个包含我们所创建的所有变量的一个巨大的数组或列表
So when we say we have some contract called Son of storage,
假如说我们有一个合约，名为 "FunWithStorage"
and we have a variable called favorite number,
其中有一个变量名为 "favoriteNumber"
we're basically saying we want this favorite number variable to persist, right,
基本上，我们的意思就是让这个 "favoriteNumber" 变量永久存在，对吧？
we saw in a lot of our examples,
我们已经见过许多例子了
we had a favorite number variable
如果我们有一个 "favoriteNumber" 变量
that we can always call to see what this contracts favorite number was,
那么我们可以随时调用并查看这个合约的 "favoriteNumber" 是什么
well, the way it persists,
它能永久存在的原因是，
is it gets stored in this place called storage.
它被存储在了一个名为 "Storage" 的地方
A storage box is this giant list associated with this contract
"Storage" 是一个与合约相关联的巨大列表
where every single variable and every single value in the storage section is slotted into a 32 byte long slot in this storage array.
其中的每个变量，每个值都被放置在了 "Storage" 数组中的某个 32 字节长的槽位中
So for example, the number 25 in its bytes implementation is 000 with a ton of zeros 19.
举个例子，这个数字 25 在字节中的表示就是 0x00 一大堆 0 然后是 19
This is the hex version of the yuan 256.
这是 uint256 的十六进制形式
This is why we do so much hex translation,
这就是为什么我们要进行大量的十六进制转换
the bytes implementation of a yuan 256.
因为这就是 uint256 的字节表示形式
And each store saw increments just like an array starting from zero.
每个存储位置都和数组一样，从 0 开始递增
So for example, our next global variable or next storage variable just gets slotted at the next slot that's available.
例如，我们的下一个全局变量或者说 storage 变量会被插入到下一个可用的槽位中
So bullions, for example, get transformed from their bull version two, their hex
例如说布尔值，就会从布尔值形式转换到它们的十六进制形式
and we modified our some bool variable to be true
我们把这个 "someBool" 变量修改为了 true
and X edition of the true Boolean 0x 001.
而 true 布尔值的十六进制版本就是 0x00...01
Every time you save an additional global variable,
每当你保存一个额外的全局变量
or more correctly, one of these storage variables,
或者更准确地说，保存一个 storage 变量时
it takes up an additional storage slot.
它都会占用一个额外的 "Storage" 槽位
And what about variables that are dynamic in length, or that can change length?
那么对于动态长度，或者说可以改变长度的变量呢？
What about something that's dynamic?
这些动态的东西怎么办？
Well, for dynamic values, like a dynamic array, or a mapping
对于动态值来说，比如动态数组或者 mapping
elements inside the array or inside the mapping are actually stored using some type of hashing function.
它们内部的元素实际上是以一种名为“哈希函数”("Hashing Function")的形式存储的
And you can see those specific functions in the documentation,
你可以在文档中查看到它的具体函数形式
the object itself does take up a storage slot,
这些对象本身确实会占用一个 "Storage" 槽位
but it's not going to be the entire array.
但它并不是整个数组
For example, my array variable here at storage, slot two
比如说，这里的 "myArray" 变量位于 "Storage" 的槽位 [2]
doesn't have the entire array in storage slot two,
并不是整个数组都位于 "Storage" 槽位 [2]
what has actually is just the array length,
它其实只代表这个数组的长度
the length of the array is stored at storage slot two.
数组的长度值被存储在了 "Storage" 槽位 [2] 上
But for example, if we do my array dot push 222,
但如果我们执行 `myArray.push(222)` 的话
we do some hashing function,
就会获得这么一个哈希函数
which again, you can see in the documentation what that is,
再次强调，你可以在文档中查看它具体是什么东西
and we'll store the number 222. At that location in storage,
而我们将在 "Storage" 的那个位置上(指哈希函数)，存储数字 222
the hex of 222 is 0x 0000 D,
222 的十六进制形式是 0x00...0de
so it gets stored in this crazy spot.
所以它就被存储在了这么一个奇怪的位置上
And this is good, this is intentional,
而且这很好，这就是有意为之的
because 32 Bytes may not be nearly big enough to store my array if our array gets massive.
因为 32 字节的大小可能远远不足以存储我的数组，如果我们的数组非常大的话
And it wouldn't make sense for to put the elements inside the array at subsequent numbers
而将数组中的元素依次放置在后续的位置上也没有什么意义
because again, the size of the array can change
还是因为，数组的大小可以改变
and you're never going to be sure how many subsequence that you need.
而你永远无法确定到底需要多少个位置才足够
So for my array, it does have a storage slot for the length
对于 "myArray" 来说，它占用一个 "Storage" 槽位存储长度
for mappings. It does have a storage spot as well
而对于 mapping，它也会占用一个 "Storage" 槽位
similar to array, but it's just blank.
和数组很相似，但它是空白的
But it's blank intentionally
不过这是故意留白的
so that solidity knows, okay, there is a mapping here,
这样 Solidity 就能知道，OK 这里有一个 mapping
and it needs a storage slot for attaching functional work correctly.
它需要一个 "Storage" 槽位来正确运行它的哈希函数
Now interestingly, constant variables and immutable variables do not take up spots in storage.
有趣的是 `constant` 变量和 `immutable` 变量并不占用 "Storage" 的空间
The reason for this is because constant variables are actually part of the contracts byte code itself,
这是因为 `constant` 变量实际上已经成为了合约字节码其本身的一部分了
which sounds a little bit weird.
听起来有些奇怪
But you can imagine
但你可以这样想
what solidity does is anytime it sees constant variables name
Solidity 看到 `constant` 变量的名字时会做什么
is it just automatically swaps it out with whatever number it actually is.
它只是自动将其替换为所对应的数字而已
So you can kind of think of not in storage is just a pointer to 123
因此你可以认为它并不在 "Storage" 中，而只是作为一个指针指向 123 而已
and it doesn't take up a storage slot.
当然也就不占用 "Storage" 的槽位了
Well when we have variables inside of a function,
而当我们在函数内部有一些变量时
those variables only exist for the duration of the function.
这些变量只存在于函数的执行期间
They don't stay inside the contract. They don't persist they're not permanent.
它们不会一直存在于合约内，不是永久存在的
So variables inside these functions like new var and other var
所以这些存在于函数内部的变量，比如 `newVar` 和 `otherVar`
do not get added to storage.
它们不会被添加到 "Storage" 中
They get added in their own memory data structure.
它们会被添加到它们自己的 "memory" 数据结构中
Which gets deleted after the function has finished running.
这种数据结构在函数运行结束后就会被删除
Now you might be asking, Okay, well, why do we need this memory keyword, especially when it comes to strings,
现在你可能会问了，为什么我们会需要这个 "memory" 关键字呢？尤其是在处理字符串的时候
we saw before that we had to say String memory.
之前我们就看到过，我们必须要声明成 "string memory"
The reason we need it for strings is because strings are technically this dynamically sized array.
原因就是，因为字符串从技术上来说就是一个动态大小的数组
And we need to tell solidity,
我们需要告诉 Solidity
hey, we're going to do this on the storage location,
嘿，我们要把它存储到 "Storage" 的位置上
or we're going to do it into the memory location where we can just wipe it.
或者是我们把它存到 "memory" 的位置上，这样我们就可以轻松地清除掉它
arrays and mappings can take up a lot more space.
数组和 mapping 会占用更多的空间
So slowly, just wants to make sure Okay, where are we working with this is it
所以 Solidity 会想要确认，我们到底在哪里处理它们
storage is a memory, you have to tell me,
是 "Storage" 还是 "memory" 你必须要告诉我
I need to know if I need to allocate space for it in our storage data structure.
我需要知道我是否需要为它们在 "Storage" 数据结构中分配空间
And again, everything here you can read in the solidity documentation.
再提醒一下，所以这些内容你都可以在 Solidity 的文档中进行查阅
Now, in the GitHub repo associated with this course,
在课程关联的 GitHub 仓库中
if you go to contracts,
如果你前往 "contracts"
we've actually got an example contract section called Fun with storage,
这里有一个 "exampleContracts" 部分，名为 "FunWithStorage"
where you can play with and look at a lot of this stuff.
你可以在这里尝试和探索很多相关内容
And we even wrote a little script called deploy storage fun,
我们甚至还写了一个名为 "deploy-storage-fun" 的小脚本
where it'll print out the storage location of some of the different variables,
它会打印出一些不同变量的 "Storage" 位置
feel free to give it a run, if you want to try
如果你想尝试一下的话，请随意
a challenge anybody to write some functions that find the storage slots of the elements of the arrays, and the mappings,
这里向大家发起一个挑战，请编写一些函数来查找数组和 mapping 的元素所在的 "Storage" 槽位
and then find the data inside of those as well.
接着再找到这些槽位内的数据
We use a function here called Get storage app,
这里我们用到了一个函数名为 `getStorageAt()`
which allows us to get the storage at any one of these slots.
它能让我们获取任意一个槽位内的数据
And this is to reinforce that
这也是为了向你强调
even if you have a function as private or internal. Anybody can still read it.
即使你将一个函数设置为 "private" 或者 "internal"，其他人也仍然可以读取它
Anybody can read anything off the blockchain.
任何人都可以从区块链上读取任何信息
And you can test it exactly what this
你可以用这个来进行精准测试
if you go ahead and get clone that or copy paste the code yourself.
如果你把它 clone 了下来或者复制粘贴到了自己的代码里
(译注: clone 是 Git 的一个功能，可以把 GitHub 上的代码库直接整个下载到本地)
You can then run yarn part at deploy dash test tags, storage.
你就可以运行 `yarn hardhat deploy --test tags storage`
And you'll run the deploy script for that storage.
接着你就会运行这个 "storage" 的部署脚本
And you'll see printing out the location of storage in each storage slot
然后你就会看到每个 "Storage" 槽位上的 "Storage" 位置信息
with a fun contract that we made as an example.
被我们所制作的 "Fun(WithStorage)" 合约示例打印出来